[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Which of the following is correct about the history of medical Microbiology?",
    "options": [
      "Koch's postulates still hold fully in times",
      "Louis Pasteur propounded the 'germ theory of disease",
      "Joseph Lister introduced the use of carbonic acid for aseptic surgery for the first time",
      "The most outstanding contribution to the development of Microbiology was made by Fracastorius",
      "None of the above is correct"
    ],
    "answer": [
      "Joseph Lister introduced the use of carbonic acid for aseptic surgery for the first time"
    ],
    "explanation": "Louis Pasteur is credited with the development of the 'germ theory of disease,' which revolutionized the understanding of infectious diseases.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["MMB Med160 1st TEST"],
    "topics": ["Medical Microbiology"],
    "course": "PATHOLOGY",
    "subcourse": "History",
    "numberofAttempt": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "An 85-year-old man with an indwelling urethral catheter due to enlarged prostate and bladder outlet obstruction presents with symptoms of urinary tract infection (UTI). Which of the specimens is suitable for diagnosing the cause of the UTI?",
    "options": [
      "Catheter urine specimen",
      "Urethral catheter tip",
      "Aliquot from the urine bag",
      "All of the above",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["None of the above"],
    "explanation": "Various specimens, including catheter urine, urethral catheter tip, and aliquot from the urine bag, can be suitable for diagnosing the cause of UTI depending on the clinical scenario.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["MMB Med160 1st TEST"],
    "topics": ["Microbiology"],
    "course": "PATHOLOGY",
    "subcourse": "Diagnostic Microbiology",
    "numberofAttempt": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "With respect to specimen and transport in microbiology, which of the following is not correct?",
    "options": [
      "Skin scrapings for the diagnosis of dermatophytosis should be obtained from the centre of tinea lesions",
      "Cary Blair medium should be used to transport to distant laboratories in anticipation of delay in processing",
      "Tissue specimens which arrive in the Microbiology laboratory in fixatives such as formalin should be rejected",
      "Lumbar puncture for cerebrospinal fluid collection must be performed under strictly aseptic condition",
      "Whenever possible, specimens for microbiology testing should be collected before administration of antibiotics"
    ],
    "answer": [
      "Skin scrapings for the diagnosis of dermatophytosis should be obtained from the centre of tinea lesions"
    ],
    "explanation": "Tissue specimens arriving in fixatives like formalin are suitable for certain tests and should not be rejected outright.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["MMB Med160 1st TEST"],
    "topics": ["Microbiology"],
    "course": "PATHOLOGY",
    "subcourse": "Diagnostic Microbiology",
    "numberofAttempt": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Which of the following is correct about normal microbial flora?",
    "options": [
      "Staphylococcus saprophyticus is the major inhabitant of the skin",
      "Gram-negative bacteria make up a large proportion of normal skin flora",
      "Anaerobic bacteria are found in gingival where oxygen tension is low",
      "More than 90% of the microbial content in feces are Obligate aerobes",
      "The normal flora of the vagina is consistent independent of age, pH, and hormonal factors"
    ],
    "explanation": "Staphylococcus epidermidis, Staphylococcus Aureus, Diphtheroids, Gram negatives bacteria, Candida albicans, Micrococci are inhabitant of the skin with Straphylococcus epidermidis being the major inhabitant of the skin,\n Gram negative bacteria make up a small proportion of normal skin flora mostly seen in intertriginous areas such as axilla and toe webs and not on dry skin, \n Anaerobic bacteria are found in gingival where oxygen tension is low,\n More than 90% of microbial content of human colon and faces are anaerobes including Bacteroides, Bifidobacterium, Eubacterium, Eubacterium and  Clostridium, \n Vaginal normal flora is dependent on age, pH and hormonal levels in the host",
    "answer": [
      "Anaerobic bacteria are found in gingival where oxygen tension is low"
    ],
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["MMB Med160 1st TEST"],
    "topics": ["NORMAL FLORA"],
    "course": "PATHOLOGY",
    "subcourse": "MEDICAL MICROBIOLOGY",
    "numberofAttempt": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Normal flora may be involved in the pathogenesis of some infectious disease processes. Which of the following are correctly paired with causative normal flora?",
    "options": [
      "Pseudomembranous colitis and Bacteroides fragilis",
      "Bacterial Vaginosis and Lactobacillus",
      "Dental caries and Actinomyces",
      "Neonatal sepsis and Streptococcus pyogenes",
      "Peritonitis and Clostridium difficile"
    ],
    "answer": ["Dental caries and Actinomyces"],
    "explanation": "Pseudomebranouse colitis and Clostridium difficile, \n Bacterial Vaginosis and Gardnarella, mobiluncus, \n Dental caries and Actinomyces and Viridans Streptococci, \n Neonatal sepsis or meningitis and Streptococcus agalactiae, \n Peritonitis and Bacteriodes fragilis",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["MMB Med160 1st TEST"],
    "topics": ["NORMAL FLORA"],
    "course": "PATHOLOGY",
    "subcourse": "MEDICAL MICROBIOLOGY",
    "numberofAttempt": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Which of these is correct with respect to Varicella-zoster virus?",
    "options": [
      "Varicella reflects the endogenous activation of the varicella-zoster virus infection",
      "Chickenpox is mild in children with leukemia or other immune defects",
      "The incubation period of chickenpox ranges from 10-21 days",
      "The most commonly affected area is the skin extending from the vertebral column and the ventral midline to extremities",
      "Reye's syndrome is a rare complication"
    ],
    "answer": ["The incubation period of chickenpox ranges from 10-21 days"],
    "explanation": "Reye's syndrome is a rare but serious complication associated with the use of aspirin in children recovering from viral infections, including chickenpox.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["MMB Med160 1st TEST"],
    "topics": ["Microbiology"],
    "course": "PATHOLOGY",
    "subcourse": "Virology",
    "numberofAttempt": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Which of these is correct with respect to Herpes simplex Viruses?",
    "options": [
      "Infection with simplex virus type I is virtually restricted to the tropical countries",
      "Infection with type I usually affects body sites below the waist, primarily the genitals",
      "Usual sites for latency for type I virus is sacral ganglia",
      "The property of producing recurrent lesions in healthy individuals is unique to type I virus",
      "Acyclovir is an established drug treatment"
    ],
    "answer": ["Acyclovir is an established drug treatment"],
    "explanation": "Herpes simplex virus type I typically establishes latency in the trigeminal ganglia, not sacral ganglia.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["MMB Med160 1st TEST"],
    "topics": ["Microbiology"],
    "course": "PATHOLOGY",
    "subcourse": "Virology",
    "numberofAttempt": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Which of these statements about Rabies infection is wrong?",
    "options": [
      "Virus transmitted by bite or scratch of rabid animal",
      "Virus does not replicate in the muscle and connective tissue portal of entry",
      "Virus replicates in the nerve cells through which the virus wanders into the CNS",
      "The virus disseminates into the peripheral organs of corneal, kidneys, salivary glands, etc.",
      "Prophylaxis includes both passive and active immunization"
    ],
    "answer": [
      "Virus does not replicate in the muscle and connective tissue portal of entry"
    ],
    "explanation": "Rabies virus initially replicates at the site of entry (usually muscle and connective tissue) before spreading to the nerve cells and then to the CNS.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["MMB Med160 1st TEST"],
    "topics": ["Microbiology"],
    "course": "PATHOLOGY",
    "subcourse": "Virology",
    "numberofAttempt": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "In the identification of bacteria",
    "options": [
      "Both positive and negative control tests are not necessary",
      "Only biochemical tests are necessary",
      "Serological tests alone are necessary",
      "A pure single colony is best",
      "Antibiotic sensitivity testing is used"
    ],
    "answer": ["A pure single colony is best"],
    "explanation": "Identification of bacteria is best achieved using a pure culture derived from a single colony to ensure accurate results.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["MMB Med160 1st TEST"],
    "topics": ["Microbiology"],
    "course": "PATHOLOGY",
    "subcourse": "Bacteriology",
    "numberofAttempt": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Septicaemia refers to",
    "options": [
      "Presence of bacteria in blood",
      "Response to a wide variety of clinical insults which include infections and non-infections causes",
      "State of elevated core temperature, which is often but not necessarily part of the defensive responses of a multicellular organism to the invasion of life or inanimate matter recognized as pathogenic or alien to the host",
      "Evidence of systemic responses to infection",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["Evidence of systemic responses to infection"],
    "explanation": "Septicaemia specifically refers to the presence of bacteria in the blood.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["MMB Med160 1st TEST"],
    "topics": ["SEPSIS"],
    "course": "PATHOLOGY",
    "subcourse": "MEDICAL MICROBIOLOGY",
    "numberofAttempt": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Systemic Inflammatory response syndrome (SIRS) refers to",
    "options": [
      "Clinical evidence of infection plus evidence of systematic response e.g hypoxia, oliguria",
      "Septic shock that lasts for less than one hour",
      "Sepsis associated with organ dysfunction hypoperfusion or hypotension",
      "None of the above",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["None of the above"],
    "explanation": "Systemic Inflammatory Response Syndrome (SIRS) is associated with a systemic response to infection, often leading to organ dysfunction, hypoperfusion, or hypotension.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["MMB Med160 1st TEST"],
    "topics": ["SEPSIS"],
    "course": "PATHOLOGY",
    "subcourse": "MEDICAL MICROBIOLOGY",
    "numberofAttempt": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Campylobacter species include",
    "options": [
      "Campylobacter faeces",
      "Campylobacter jejuni",
      "Campylobacter colon",
      "Campylobacter pylori",
      "Campylobacter haemophylis"
    ],
    "answer": ["Campylobacter jejuni"],
    "explanation": "Among the options, Campylobacter jejuni is a species associated with Campylobacter infections in humans.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["MMB Med160 1st TEST"],
    "topics": ["Microbiology"],
    "course": "PATHOLOGY",
    "subcourse": "Bacteriology",
    "numberofAttempt": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "The following is true about Campylobacter species except",
    "options": [
      "Gram negative",
      "Urease positive",
      "'S'-shaped bacilli",
      "Cause bloody diarrhea",
      "Drug of choice is erythromycin"
    ],
    "answer": ["Urease positive"],
    "explanation": "Campylobacter species are urease negative; they do not produce urease.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["MMB Med160 1st TEST"],
    "topics": ["Microbiology"],
    "course": "PATHOLOGY",
    "subcourse": "Bacteriology",
    "numberofAttempt": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Microorganisms exhibit defense mechanisms against the immune system by",
    "options": [
      "Having capsules",
      "Not mutating",
      "Staining with dyes",
      "Getting engulfed",
      "Not producing biofilms"
    ],
    "answer": ["Having capsules"],
    "explanation": "Biofilm formation is a defense mechanism used by microorganisms against the immune system.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["MMB Med160 1st TEST"],
    "topics": ["Microbiology"],
    "course": "PATHOLOGY",
    "subcourse": "Immunology",
    "numberofAttempt": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Malaria-causing parasites include the following except:",
    "options": [
      "Plasmodium knowlesi",
      "Plasmodium ovale",
      "Plasmodium haemophylis",
      "Plasmodium malariae",
      "Plasmodium vivax"
    ],
    "answer": ["Plasmodium haemophylis"],
    "explanation": "Plasmodium haemophylis is not a recognized species causing malaria.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["MMB Med160 1st TEST"],
    "topics": ["Microbiology"],
    "course": "PATHOLOGY",
    "subcourse": "Parasitology",
    "numberofAttempt": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Antimalaria drugs include",
    "options": [
      "Artemisinin-based combinations",
      "Penicillin",
      "Amoxicillin",
      "Chloramphenicol",
      "Metronidazole"
    ],
    "answer": ["Artemisinin-based combinations"],
    "explanation": "Artemisinin-based combinations are commonly used as antimalarial drugs.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["MMB Med160 1st TEST"],
    "topics": ["Pharmacology"],
    "course": "PATHOLOGY",
    "subcourse": "Parasitology",
    "numberofAttempt": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Haemophilus influenzae characteristics:",
    "options": [
      "Growth on nutrient agar",
      "Growth on C.L.E.D Agar",
      "Cocci morphology",
      "Gram positive",
      "Exhibits satellitism"
    ],
    "answer": ["Exhibits satellitism"],
    "explanation": "Haemophilus influenzae exhibits satellitism, where it requires the presence of Staphylococcus aureus to grow on culture media.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["MMB Med160 1st TEST"],
    "topics": ["Microbiology"],
    "course": "PATHOLOGY",
    "subcourse": "Bacteriology",
    "numberofAttempt": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "About the Staphylococci: Which statement is most correct?",
    "options": [
      "They are found only on humans and animals.",
      "They are generally sensitive to the tetracyclines.",
      "The most virulent species of the genus is S.pneumoniae.",
      "S.epidermidis is known to contaminate culture media and infect prosthetic implants.",
      "S.saphrophyticus causes urinary tract infection (UTI)"
    ],
    "answer": ["S. epidermidis causes urinary tract infection (UTI)"],
    "explanation": "S.saphrophyticus is the 2nd leading(1st is E.coli) cause of urinary tract infection in sexually active young women",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["MMB Med160 1st TEST"],
    "topics": ["Microbiology"],
    "course": "PATHOLOGY",
    "subcourse": "Bacteriology",
    "numberofAttempt": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "About S.aureus: Which statement is most correct?",
    "options": [
      "It is a catalase positive and coagulase positive staphylococcus",
      "It possesses the superantigen SPE-A, SPE-B, and SPE-C.",
      "It is capable of causing scarlet fever, bullous impetigo, and erysipelas.",
      "Staphylococcus food poisoning is better treated with vancomycin.",
      "A patient with an abscess collection who had S. aureus isolated from his blood should ideally incision and drainage of the abscess only; adding antibiotics to the treatment is a waste of resources."
    ],
    "answer": [
      "It is a catalase positive and coagulase positive staphylococcus"
    ],
    "explanation": "S.aureus is a gram positive, beta hemolytic, catalase positive, coagulase positive cocci, which lie in grape like clutters on gram stain with elaborate golden pigment when culture in sheep blood agar",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["MMB Med160 1st TEST"],
    "topics": ["Microbiology"],
    "course": "PATHOLOGY",
    "subcourse": "Bacteriology",
    "numberofAttempt": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "S. pyogenes can be distinguished from other β- hemolytic Streptococcus by which of the following laboratory tests?",
    "options": [
      "Inhibition of optochin",
      "Activation of C-reactive protein",
      "Hydrolysis of Esculin in the presence of bile salts",
      "Inhibition of Bacitracin",
      "None of the above is correct"
    ],
    "answer": ["None of the above is correct"],
    "explanation": "Streptococcus pyogenes can be distinguished from other β-hemolytic Streptococcus by its susceptibility to bacitracin.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["MMB Med160 1st TEST"],
    "topics": ["Microbiology"],
    "course": "PATHOLOGY",
    "subcourse": "Bacteriology",
    "numberofAttempt": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 21,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Which of the following best describes the pathogenesis of acute rheumatic fever?",
    "options": [
      "Antibody to M-protein of S. pyogenes cross reacts with antigens in cardiac tissues and synovial joint membranes",
      "A superantigen exotoxin by S. pyogenes attacks and damages cardiac and joint tissues.",
      "Endotoxin produced by S. pyogenes activates macrophages which invade and damage cardiac and joint tissues",
      "S.pneumoniae autolysin damages cardiac and joint tissues",
      "Indiscriminate deposition of rheumatoid cardiac and joint tissues"
    ],
    "answer": [
      "Antibody to M-protein of S. pyogenes cross reacts with antigens in cardiac tissues and synovial joint membranes"
    ],
    "explanation": "Acute rheumatic fever pathogenesis involves the cross-reaction of antibodies to the M-protein of Streptococcus pyogenes with antigens in cardiac tissues and synovial joint membranes.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["MMB Med160 1st TEST"],
    "topics": ["Microbiology"],
    "course": "PATHOLOGY",
    "subcourse": "MEDICAL MICROBIOLOGY",
    "numberofAttempt": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 22,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "An 80-year—old man with endocarditis caused by Enterococcus faecalis will be better treated with which of the following combination of antibiotics?",
    "options": [
      "Pernoxacin and doxycycline",
      "Rifampicin and chloramphenicol",
      "Clindamycin and azithromycin",
      "Penicillin and gentamicin",
      "None of the above is correct"
    ],
    "answer": ["Penicillin and gentamicin"],
    "explanation": "Endocarditis caused by Enterococcus faecalis is often treated with a combination of penicillin and gentamicin.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["MMB Med160 1st TEST"],
    "topics": ["Microbiology"],
    "course": "PATHOLOGY",
    "subcourse": "MEDICAL MICROBIOLOGY",
    "numberofAttempt": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 23,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "A potent exotoxin produced by S. aureus that kills mammalian cells and is important in severe, spreading necrotizing lesions caused by MRSA strain is:",
    "options": [
      "Coagulase",
      "Enterotoxin",
      "Panton-valentine Leukocidin (PVL)",
      "Staphyloxanthin",
      "Autolysin"
    ],
    "answer": ["Panton-valentine Leukocidin (PVL)"],
    "explanation": "Panton-valentine Leukocidin (PVL) is a potent exotoxin produced by S. aureus, and it plays a role in severe, spreading necrotizing lesions caused by MRSA strains.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["MMB Med160 1st TEST"],
    "topics": ["Microbiology"],
    "course": "PATHOLOGY",
    "subcourse": "Bacteriology",
    "numberofAttempt": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 24,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Which one of the following antibiotics is most appropriate in treating the above infection caused by MRSA?",
    "options": [
      "Amoxicillin",
      "Ciprofloxacin",
      "Vancomycin",
      "Ceftriaxone",
      "Cefotaxime"
    ],
    "answer": ["Vancomycin"],
    "explanation": "Vancomycin is often the most appropriate antibiotic for treating infections caused by MRSA (Methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus).",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["MMB Med160 1st TEST"],
    "topics": ["Microbiology"],
    "course": "PATHOLOGY",
    "subcourse": "Bacteriology",
    "numberofAttempt": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 25,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Superantigen produced by S.aureus is involved in the pathogenesis of which one of the following disease?",
    "options": [
      "Osteomyelitis",
      "Septicaemia",
      "Scarlet fever",
      "Toxic shock syndrome",
      "Endocarditis"
    ],
    "answer": ["Toxic shock syndrome"],
    "explanation": "Superantigens produced by S. aureus are involved in the pathogenesis of Toxic Shock Syndrome.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["MMB Med160 1st TEST"],
    "topics": ["Microbiology"],
    "course": "PATHOLOGY",
    "subcourse": "MEDICAL MICROBIOLOGY",
    "numberofAttempt": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 26,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "An outbreak of pneumococcal pneumonia and sepsis has occurred among inmates of a prison. Which virulence factor must have contributed to this outbreak?",
    "options": [
      "Flagellar protein",
      "Capsule",
      "Peptidoglycan",
      "Pilus protein",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["Capsule"],
    "explanation": "The capsule is a virulence factor that contributes to the pathogenicity of pneumococcal pneumonia and sepsis.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["MMB Med160 1st TEST"],
    "topics": ["Microbiology"],
    "course": "PATHOLOGY",
    "subcourse": "Bacteriology",
    "numberofAttempt": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 27,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "While screening blood donation, a donor's HBV test result is as follows: HBsAg -ve & Anti-HBsAg +ve. Which of these is most appropriate about the donor?",
    "options": [
      "She is suffering from acute HBV infection",
      "Currently, no evidence of protection against HBV infection",
      "She had either HBV infection or HBV vaccination in the past",
      "She is susceptible to HBV infection",
      "Donor is not eligible for blood donation"
    ],
    "answer": ["She had either HBV infection or HBV vaccination in the past"],
    "explanation": "A donor with HBsAg -ve & Anti-HBsAg +ve has either had HBV infection in the past or has been vaccinated against HBV.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["MMB Med160 1st TEST"],
    "topics": ["Microbiology"],
    "course": "PATHOLOGY",
    "subcourse": "Immunology",
    "numberofAttempt": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 28,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Which one of these statements about Hepadnaviridae is false?",
    "options": [
      "Hepatitis A and B belong to this family and they possess DNA genome",
      "In infected HBV present in the blood, serum, semen and saliva.",
      "HBV co-infection with HDV a defective RNA virus can occur.",
      "HBsAg positively indicates presence of live HBV in an infected individual.",
      "Liver cirrhosis hepatocellular carcinoma and hepatic failure are complications of its infection"
    ],
    "answer": [
      "Hepatitis A and B belong to this family and they possess DNA genome"
    ],
    "explanation": "Liver cirrhosis, hepatocellular carcinoma, and hepatic failure are complications associated with chronic Hepatitis B infection, not Hepadnaviridae in general.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["MMB Med160 1st TEST"],
    "topics": ["Microbiology"],
    "course": "PATHOLOGY",
    "subcourse": "Virology",
    "numberofAttempt": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 29,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Which one of these statements is false about Viral hepatitis B infection?",
    "options": [
      "It can be transmitted if infected fluid reaches conjunctiva of the eye",
      "Presence of anti-HBS antibody signifies active infection",
      "Chronic infection can lead to liver cirrhosis",
      "It is sexually transmissible",
      "Adefovir and lamivudine are useful in treating Chronic infection"
    ],
    "answer": ["Presence of anti-HBS antibody signifies active infection"],
    "explanation": "Presence of anti-HBS antibody signifies immunity or past infection, not active infection.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["MMB Med160 1st TEST"],
    "topics": ["Microbiology"],
    "course": "PATHOLOGY",
    "subcourse": "Virology",
    "numberofAttempt": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 30,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Which of the following is most correct about antibodies/antigens?",
    "options": [
      "Superantigens are capable of stimulating a large pool of T-cells, consequently leading to large quantities of cytokines causing deleterious effects such as shock.",
      "Antigens that bind to antibodies but are incapable of triggering immune response are referred to as immunogens.",
      "Secretory IgA antagonizes microbes on the skin of the body",
      "IgE cannot activate complement and cannot agglutinate antigens.",
      "IgM can cross the placenta to confer immunity to the fetus."
    ],
    "answer": [
      "IgE cannot activate complement and cannot agglutinate antigens."
    ],
    "explanation": "IgE is involved in allergic responses and does not activate complement or agglutinate antigens.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["MMB Med160 1st TEST"],
    "topics": ["Microbiology"],
    "course": "PATHOLOGY",
    "subcourse": "Immunology",
    "numberofAttempt": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 31,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Which is most correct about the immune response to infections?",
    "options": [
      "Immune response to intracellular bacterial infection is mainly antibody-mediated.",
      "Neutrophils and basophils are involved in cell-mediated immune response called antibody cell-mediated cytotoxicity (ADCC).",
      "Earliest adaptive responses for clearance of intracellular infection are often delayed hypersensitivity (DTH) reactions generated by CD4+ cells.",
      "Schistosome and Plasmodium cannot acquire host antigens on their surfaces in order to evade the immune response.",
      "S. aureus is known to suppress both humoral and cell-mediated immune responses."
    ],
    "answer": [
      "Earliest adaptive responses for clearance of intracellular infection are often delayed hypersensitivity (DTH) reactions generated by CD4+ cells."
    ],
    "explanation": "Delayed hypersensitivity reactions generated by CD4+ cells are part of the early adaptive responses for the clearance of intracellular infections.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["MMB Med160 1st TEST"],
    "topics": ["Microbiology"],
    "course": "PATHOLOGY",
    "subcourse": "Immunology",
    "numberofAttempt": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 32,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Immune response to helminthic infections:",
    "options": [
      "There is neutrophilia in most cases",
      "ADCC is never involved",
      "There is decreased IgE level in most helminthic infections",
      "Activated macrophages attracted to the site of helminthic infections destroy all the helminths.",
      "None of the above is correct"
    ],
    "answer": ["There is decreased IgE level in most helminthic infections"],
    "explanation": "The statement 'None of the above is correct' is the most appropriate response, as helminthic infections do not typically result in neutrophilia, involve ADCC, or lead to decreased IgE levels.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["MMB Med160 1st TEST"],
    "topics": ["Microbiology"],
    "course": "PATHOLOGY",
    "subcourse": "Immunology",
    "numberofAttempt": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 33,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "About the immunoglobulins, identify the most correct statement.",
    "options": [
      "IgE can activate the complement system and agglutinate antigens.",
      "IgG & IgM can cross the blood/brain barrier to reach the fetus.",
      "IgD acts as a receptor on the surface of B-cells",
      "IgD & IgE levels rise in the serum following parasitic infections.",
      "None of the above is correct"
    ],
    "answer": ["IgD acts as a receptor on the surface of B-cells"],
    "explanation": "IgD acts as a receptor on the surface of B-cells, contributing to the activation of B-cells.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["MMB Med160 1st TEST"],
    "topics": ["Microbiology"],
    "course": "PATHOLOGY",
    "subcourse": "Immunology",
    "numberofAttempt": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 34,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Which one of the following is most correct about the superantigens:",
    "options": [
      "They bind to B cells specifically in association with class II MHC molecules.",
      "They stimulate about 500% of B cell population in the bloodstream.",
      "They are specifically produced by bacteria only.",
      "They do not undergo normal processing by APC cells.",
      "None of the above is correct"
    ],
    "answer": ["They do not undergo normal processing by APC cells."],
    "explanation": "Superantigens do not undergo normal processing by APC cells and activate a large proportion of T-cells directly.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["MMB Med160 1st TEST"],
    "topics": ["Microbiology"],
    "course": "PATHOLOGY",
    "subcourse": "Immunology",
    "numberofAttempt": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 35,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Which of these vectors transmits leishmaniasis?",
    "options": [
      "Cockroach (Blattella sp.)",
      "Tsetse fly (Glossina sp.)",
      "Blackfly (Simulium sp.)",
      "Sandfly (Phlebotomus sp.)",
      "Stable fly (Stomoxys sp.)"
    ],
    "answer": ["Sandfly (Phlebotomus sp.)"],
    "explanation": "Leishmaniasis is transmitted by the bite of infected sandflies (Phlebotomus sp.).",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["MMB Med160 1st TEST"],
    "topics": ["Microbiology"],
    "course": "PATHOLOGY",
    "subcourse": "Parasitology",
    "numberofAttempt": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 36,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Concerning trypanosomiasis, which statement is correct?",
    "options": [
      "Chaga's disease is transmitted through the saliva of reduviid bugs",
      "African trypanosomiasis is caused by Trypanosoma cruzi",
      "Suramin is effective for treatment of neurological stage of African trypanosomiasis",
      "Romana's sign is typical of early stage Chaga's disease",
      "African trypanosomiasis caused by T. brucei gambiense is very rapid in onset and rapidly progresses to death"
    ],
    "answer": ["Romana's sign is typical of early stage Chaga's disease"],
    "explanation": "Romana's sign is a characteristic feature of Chaga's disease and is observed in the early stage of the infection.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["MMB Med160 1st TEST"],
    "topics": ["Microbiology"],
    "course": "PATHOLOGY",
    "subcourse": "Parasitology",
    "numberofAttempt": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 37,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Which of these is true about the developmental stages of haemoflagellates?",
    "options": [
      "Trypomastigotes and promastigotes are harboured within insect vectors",
      "Promastigotes are the infective form transmitted to man in trypanosomiasis",
      "Amastigotes possess an undulating membrane",
      "Epimastigotes are responsible for central nervous system infection in African trypanosomiasis",
      "Amastigotes are the forms found in the heart in Chaga's disease."
    ],
    "answer": [
      "Amastigotes are the forms found in the heart in Chaga's disease."
    ],
    "explanation": "Amastigotes of haemoflagellates possess an undulating membrane, which is a characteristic feature of this developmental stage.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["MMB Med160 1st TEST"],
    "topics": ["Microbiology"],
    "course": "PATHOLOGY",
    "subcourse": "Parasitology",
    "numberofAttempt": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 38,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Giardiasis",
    "options": [
      "Aetiology is Trichomonas hominis",
      "May be spread through the respiratory route",
      "Is transmitted by ingestion of the uninucleate cyst in contaminated water",
      "May cause malabsorption syndrome",
      "Results in bloody diarrhoea"
    ],
    "answer": ["May cause malabsorption syndrome"],
    "explanation": "Giardiasis is caused by Giardia lamblia and is transmitted by the ingestion of the uninucleate cyst in contaminated water.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["MMB Med160 1st TEST"],
    "topics": ["Microbiology"],
    "course": "PATHOLOGY",
    "subcourse": "Parasitology",
    "numberofAttempt": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 39,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Trichomonas vaginalis",
    "options": [
      "Is transmitted sexually",
      "Infection may be asymptomatic",
      "Is diagnosed by finding cysts on microscopy of genital smears",
      "Is transmitted sexually and Is diagnosed by finding cysts on microscopy of genital smears are correct",
      "None of the above is correct"
    ],
    "answer": [
      "Is transmitted sexually and Is diagnosed by finding cysts on microscopy of genital smears are correct"
    ],
    "explanation": "Trichomonas vaginalis is transmitted sexually, and the infection may be asymptomatic in some cases.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["MMB Med160 1st TEST"],
    "topics": ["Microbiology"],
    "course": "PATHOLOGY",
    "subcourse": "Parasitology",
    "numberofAttempt": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 40,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Which of the following is not a characteristic of fungi?",
    "options": [
      "They are eukaryotic",
      "They possess a rigid cell wall",
      "They are autotrophic",
      "They possess a cell membrane composed of ergosterol",
      "They may be unicellular or multicellular"
    ],
    "answer": ["They are autotrophic"],
    "explanation": "Fungi are heterotrophic, meaning they obtain nutrients from organic matter, and they are not autotrophic.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["MMB Med160 1st TEST"],
    "topics": ["Microbiology"],
    "course": "PATHOLOGY",
    "subcourse": "Mycology",
    "numberofAttempt": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 41,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Select the fungus that is not dimorphic",
    "options": [
      "Sporothrix schenckii",
      "Blastomyces dermatitidis",
      "Talaromyces marneffei",
      "Emmonsia africanus",
      "Basidiobolus ranarum"
    ],
    "answer": ["Basidiobolus ranarum"],
    "explanation": "Basidiobolus ranarum is not dimorphic. It exists only in the hyphal form.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["MMB Med160 1st TEST"],
    "topics": ["Microbiology"],
    "course": "PATHOLOGY",
    "subcourse": "Mycology",
    "numberofAttempt": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 42,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Characteristics of dermatophytes",
    "options": [
      "Aseptate moulds",
      "Dimorphic",
      "Dematiaceous moulds",
      "Keratinophilic",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["Keratinophilic"],
    "explanation": "Dermatophytes are fungi that are keratinophilic, meaning they have a preference for keratin-containing tissues like skin, hair, and nails.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["MMB Med160 1st TEST"],
    "topics": ["Microbiology"],
    "course": "PATHOLOGY",
    "subcourse": "Mycology",
    "numberofAttempt": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 43,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Which of these statements is correct?",
    "options": [
      "Jock itch is tenia of the skin of the genitals",
      "Piedra is an infection of the urogenital system",
      "Oral ketoconazole is not effective in the treatment of Pityriasis versicolor",
      "Tinea nigra is caused by a yeast",
      "Kerion is an inflammatory lesion of the finger and toe nails caused by zoophilic dermatophytes"
    ],
    "answer": ["Jock itch is tenia of the skin of the genitals"],
    "explanation": "Kerion is a specific type of inflammatory fungal infection affecting the nails, caused by zoophilic dermatophytes.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["MMB Med160 1st TEST"],
    "topics": ["Microbiology"],
    "course": "PATHOLOGY",
    "subcourse": "Mycology",
    "numberofAttempt": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 44,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Fungi implicated in the etiology of superficial mycosis",
    "options": [
      "Aspergillus",
      "Candida",
      "Microsporum",
      "Epidermophyton",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["All of the above"],
    "explanation": "Aspergillus, Candida, Microsporum, and Epidermophyton are fungi implicated in the etiology of superficial mycosis.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["MMB Med160 1st TEST"],
    "topics": ["Microbiology"],
    "course": "PATHOLOGY",
    "subcourse": "Mycology",
    "numberofAttempt": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 45,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "An elderly diabetic woman had exploratory laparotomy for intestinal obstruction and was admitted into the intensive care unit post-op. A central venous catheter was inserted for venous access, and she was treated with meropenem. Which of the following conditions may predispose her to invasive candidiasis?",
    "options": [
      "Use of broad-spectrum antibiotics",
      "Poorly controlled diabetes mellitus",
      "Presence of central venous catheters",
      "Abdominal surgery",
      "All options are correct"
    ],
    "answer": ["All options are correct"],
    "explanation": "Conditions such as the use of broad-spectrum antibiotics, poorly controlled diabetes mellitus, presence of central venous catheters, and abdominal surgery may predispose to invasive candidiasis.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["MMB Med160 1st TEST"],
    "topics": ["Microbiology"],
    "course": "PATHOLOGY",
    "subcourse": "Mycology",
    "numberofAttempt": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 46,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "A 25-year-old female with frequent and painful urination. Microscopic and culture results confirmed the cause as Escherichia coli. Which of these features aided in identification?",
    "options": [
      "Gram-positive bacilli",
      "Lactose fermentation on Maconkey agar",
      "Indole negativity",
      "Oxidase positivity",
      "Absence of motility"
    ],
    "answer": ["Lactose fermentation on Maconkey agar"],
    "explanation": "Escherichia coli is known for its ability to ferment lactose, and this characteristic is often used in its identification, especially on Maconkey agar.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["MMB Med160 1st TEST"],
    "topics": ["Microbiology"],
    "course": "PATHOLOGY",
    "subcourse": "Bacteriology",
    "numberofAttempt": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 47,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Which of the following antibacterial agents is useful in the treatment of a fifteen-year-old female diagnosed with Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection?",
    "options": [
      "Amoxicillin",
      "Ampicillin",
      "Vancomycin",
      "Ceftriaxone",
      "Azithromycin"
    ],
    "answer": ["Azithromycin"],
    "explanation": "Azithromycin is effective against Mycoplasma pneumoniae and is commonly used in the treatment of infections caused by this organism.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["MMB Med160 1st TEST"],
    "topics": ["ANTIBACTERIAL CHEMOTHERAPY", "ANTIBACTERIAL AGENTS"],
    "course": "MEDICAL MICROBIOLOGY",
    "subcourse": "Bacteriology",
    "numberofAttempt": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 48,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Antibacterial resistance can be mediated by",
    "options": [
      "Drug inactivating enzymes",
      "Drug efflux pumps",
      "Modification of drug target",
      "All of the above",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["All of the above"],
    "explanation": "Antibacterial resistance can be mediated by various mechanisms, including drug inactivating enzymes, drug efflux pumps, and modification of drug targets.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["MMB Med160 1st TEST"],
    "topics": ["ANTIBACTERIAL CHEMOTHERAPY", "ANTIBACTERIAL AGENTS"],
    "course": "MEDICAL MICROBIOLOGY",
    "subcourse": "PATHOLOGY",
    "numberofAttempt": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 49,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "A 30-year-old woman is for burns and developed Pseudomonas infection of the wound. Which of the antibiotics will be useful for treatment?",
    "options": [
      "Azithromycin",
      "Piperacillin-tazobactam",
      "Amoxicillin-clavulanic acid (Co-amoxiclav)",
      "Nitrofurantoin",
      "Vancomycin"
    ],
    "answer": ["Piperacillin-tazobactam"],
    "explanation": "Piperacillin-tazobactam is effective against Pseudomonas infections and is commonly used in the treatment of such infections, especially in burn patients.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["MMB Med160 1st TEST"],
    "topics": ["ANTIBACTERIAL CHEMOTHERAPY", "ANTIBACTERIAL AGENTS"],
    "course": "MEDICAL MICROBIOLOGY",
    "subcourse": "PATHOLOGY",
    "numberofAttempt": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 50,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Which of the following antibacterials is rightly paired with the site of action?",
    "options": [
      "Doxycycline - 30S Ribosomal subunit",
      "Vancomycin - 50S Ribosomal subunit",
      "Chloramphenicol - 30S Ribosomal subunit",
      "Gentamicin - 50S Ribosomal subunit",
      "Erythromycin - 30S Ribosomal subunit"
    ],
    "answer": ["Doxycycline - 30S Ribosomal subunit"],
    "explanation": "Doxycycline acts on the 30S ribosomal subunit, inhibiting protein synthesis in bacteria.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["MMB Med160 1st TEST"],
    "topics": ["ANTIBACTERIAL CHEMOTHERAPY", "ANTIBACTERIAL AGENTS"],
    "course": "MEDICAL MICROBIOLOGY",
    "subcourse": "PATHOLOGY",
    "numberofAttempt": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  }
]
